A Guide to the Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc. records FA085
Rockefeller Archive Center
- DLMA, Inc., 1957-1995; 2; 78.875 Cubic Feet 214 document cases
  - Corporate Records, 2.1
    - Financial Records, 1957-1995; 2.1.6; 8.575 Cubic Feet 19 document cases
      - Voucher Register - DMA, Inc., May 1, 1957-June 17, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 716)
      - Voucher Register #1 of Accounts Payable - D-LMA, Inc., June 18, 1958-December 31, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 717)
      - Voucher Register #2 - D-LMA, Inc., January 1, 1962-April 1966 (Box 48, Folder 718)
      - Voucher Register - D-LMA, Inc., May 1966-December 1969 (Box 48, Folder 719)
      - Voucher Register, January 1, 1970-October 31, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 720)
      - Voucher Register, November 1973-August 1978 (Box 48, Folder 721)
      - Voucher Register, September 1978-August (?) 1984 (Box 48, Folder 722)
      - Voucher Register, October 1984-July 1990 (Box 48, Folder 723)
      - Voucher Register, August 1990-December 1994 (Box 48, Folder 724)
      - Account Book (Cash Receipts or Petty Cash?), 1991-1994 (Box 48, Folder 725)
      - Payroll Journal, 1982-1984 (Box 48, Folder 726)
      - D-LMA Journal - Assets, Liabilities, General Fund, Income, Expenses, Payroll, 1988-1994 (Box 48, Folder 727)
      - Meetings - General - Budget, 1958-1960 (Box 49, Folder 728)
      - Budget Recapitulation, 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 729)
      - Budget Recapitulation, 1962-1963 (Box 49, Folder 730)
      - Budget (DLMA, Inc.), 1965 (Box 49, Folder 731)
      - Budget (DLMA, Inc.), 1966 (Box 49, Folder 732)
      - 1981 Budget and Miscellaneous Financial Data (Box 49, Folder 733)
      - Budget and Projected Report on Outstanding Dues, 1980-1982 (Box 49, Folder 734)
      - Budget and Audit, 1982-1985 (Box 49, Folder 735)
      - Budgets - DLMA, Inc. - Actual and Proposed, 1969-1994 (Box 49, Folder 736)
      - Ledger Sheets, 1970-1980 (Box 50, Folder 737)
      - Ledgers, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 738)
      - General Ledger and Financial Statements, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 739)
      - Monthly Financial Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 51, Folder 740)
        Bound.
      - Monthly Financial Statements, 1966-1969 (Box 51, Folder 741)
      - Abstract, December 31, 1968 - Used at Annual Meeting, February 1969 (Box 51, Folder 742)
      - Abstract - 1969 Financial Report (Box 51, Folder 743)
      - Abstract - 1970 Financial Report (Box 51, Folder 744)
      - Monthly Financial Statements, 1970-1972 (Box 51, Folder 745)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 51, Folder 746)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 747)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 52, Folder 748)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 749)
        Bound. With revised 1979 annual report and abstract.
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 52, Folder 750)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 751)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 752)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 53, Folder 753)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 53, Folder 754)
      - Monthly Financial Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 53, Folder 755)
      - Financial Statements, 1988-1995 (Box 54, Folder 756)
        Fiscal year 1994.
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1958-1962 (Box 54, Folder 757)
        These are financial annual reports for each year from 1958-1994 (one report for each year). Each one is essentially a short audit report as of December 31 of each given year. The actual date of the report is January or February of the following year.
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1963-1968 (Box 54, Folder 758)
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1969-1973 (Box 54, Folder 759)
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1974-1978 (Box 54, Folder 760)
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1979-1983 (Box 54, Folder 761)
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1984-1988 (Box 54, Folder 762)
      - "Annual Report of Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc." - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Certified Public Accountants), New York City, 1989-1994 (Box 54, Folder 763)
      - Bank Reconciliations, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 764)
      - Interest Income (Box 55, Folder 765)
      - DLMA - Adjusting Journal Entries, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 766)
      - "Old Ledgers", 1958-1986 (Box 55, Folder 767)
        Journal entries for membership, bank account transactions, general ledger activities, etc.
      - Accounting Entries and Journals, 1980s (Box 55, Folder 768)
      - Payroll Records, 1985-1986 (Box 55, Folder 769)
      - Payroll - Monthly (and Semi-Monthly), 1988-1991 (Box 55, Folder 770)
      - Payroll Development W/C Yearly, 1967, 1976-1982 (Box 55, Folder 771)
      - Payroll Sheets - W2s, W3s, W4s, 1980-1981 (Box 55, Folder 772)
      - Payroll Worksheets - W2s, W3s, 1981, 1982, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 773)
      - Insurance - CNA Insurance, 1982-1993 (Box 55, Folder 774)
        Includes Zurich Insurance Company and Vorbach Company material.
      - Insurance - Continental Assurance Company (Box 55, Folder 775)
        New York State Disability Benefit Insurance.
      - Insurance - John L. Vorbach Company (Insurance Brokers) - Multi-Peril Package, 1988-1995 (Box 56, Folder 776)
      - Insurance - John L. Vorbach Company (Insurance Brokers) - Workers Compensation, 1980-1995 (Box 56, Folder 777)
      - Insurance - Zurich Insurance Company - Workman's Compensation - New York State Department of Banking (NYSDB) Insurance Reports (Box 56, Folder 778)
      - Insurance - Workman's Compensation Forms and Instructions (Box 56, Folder 779)
      - Insurance - Federal Unemployment Insurance Tax Returns, 1959-1982 (Box 56, Folder 780)
      - Insurance - New York State Unemployment Insurance Returns, 1958-1975 (Box 56, Folder 781)
      - Insurance - New York State Unemployment Insurance Returns, 1976-1977 (Box 56, Folder 782)
      - Insurance - New York State Unemployment Insurance, 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 783)
      - Insurance - New York State Unemployment Insurance, 1980-1983 (Box 56, Folder 784)
      - Insurance - New York State - Department of Labor - Standard Unemployment Insurance (SUI), 1983-1995 (Box 56, Folder 785)
      - Insurance - "Theft - May 07, 1992" (Box 56, Folder 786)
        This folder is insurance claims for theft and fire damage, 1992.
      - Federal Taxes - Form 940 and Form 940EZ - Employer's Annual Federal Unemployment (FUTA) Tax Return, 1983-1994 (Box 57, Folder 787)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 940 - Employer's Annual Federal Unemployment (FUTA) Tax Return, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 788)
      - Federal Taxes - Taxes, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 789)
        Federal and New York State tax information.
      - Federal Taxes - Taxes, 1958-1969 (Box 57, Folder 790)
        Includes forms for the tax years 1959-1968.
      - Federal Taxes - DLMA Federal Quarterly Tax Returns, 1958-1964 (Box 57, Folder 791)
      - Federal Taxes - Tax Exemptions, 1959-1973 (Box 57, Folder 792)
      - Federal Taxes - D-LMA Office - Finances - By-Laws (General), 1965-1967 (Box 57, Folder 793)
      - Federal Taxes - McGrath, Doyle and Phair (Auditors), 1959-1967 (Box 57, Folder 794)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 990 - "Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax", 1969-1982 (Box 57, Folder 795)
        Tax Year: 1969-1981
      - Federal Taxes - Internal Revenue Service - U.S. Annual Information Return, 1971-1976 (Box 57, Folder 796)
        Tax Year: 1970-1975.
      - Federal Taxes - Employers Quarterly Federal Tax Return - Form 941, 1977-1979 (Box 57, Folder 797)
      - Federal Taxes - Employer's Federal Quarterly Tax REturn and Federal Tax Payment Transmittal - Form 941, 1979-1980 (Box 57, Folder 798)
      - Federal Taxes - J-51 Tax Exemption and Abatement, 1976-1981 (Box 58, Folder 799)
        D-LMA, Inc.
      - Federal Taxes - Federal Payment Transmittal Forms, 1981-1983 (Box 58, Folder 800)
      - Federal Taxes, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 801)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 941 - "Employers Federal Quarterly Tax Return", 1981-1985 (Box 58, Folder 802)
        Tax Years: 1980-1984
      - Federal Taxes - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Correspodnence - Overpayment/Underpayment, 1983-1987 (Box 58, Folder 803)
      - Federal Taxes, 1983-1985 (Box 58, Folder 804)
      - Federal Taxes, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 805)
        With Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Correspondence, 1987-1988.
      - Federal Taxes - Form 990 - "Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax", 1959-1995 (Box 58, Folder 806)
        Tax Years: 1984-1994
      - Federal Taxes - W3 Form - Transmittal of Wage and Tax Statements (Box 58, Folder 807)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 1096 - "Annual Summary and Transmittal of U. S. Information Returns" (Box 59, Folder 808)
        Tax Years: 1985-1994
      - Federal Taxes - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Correspondence, 1984-1995 (Box 59, Folder 809)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 941 - DLMA - "Employer's Quarterly Federal Tax Return", 1985-1991 (Box 59, Folder 810)
        Deposit receipts.
      - Federal Taxes - W4 Form - "Employee's Withholding Allowance Certificate" (Box 59, Folder 811)
        Tax Years: 1985-1992
      - Federal Taxes and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Correspondence, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 812)
      - Federal Taxes, 1987-1989 (Box 59, Folder 813)
        Mostly Form 941 "Employers Quarterly Federal Tax Return."
      - Federal Taxes - W9 Form - "Taxpayer Identification Number and Certification", 1988-1995 (Box 59, Folder 814)
      - Federal Taxes - Form 941 - "Employer's Quarterly Federal Tax Return", 1992-1995 (Box 59, Folder 815)
      - Federal Taxes - Federal Tax Deposit Coupon Books, 1986-1992 (Box 59, Folder 816)
      - Federal Taxes - Taxes (Checks), 1983-1985 (Box 59, Folder 817)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Income Tax, 1959-1977 (Box 60, Folder 818)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York City Earnings Tax, 1975-1976 (Box 60, Folder 819)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York City/New York State Withholding Taxes, 1978-1979 (Box 60, Folder 820)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - Sales Tax New York, 1969-1979 (Box 60, Folder 821)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - Taxation - New York State - Employer's Quarterly Report of Wages, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 822)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Income Tax Payments, 1981-1983 (Box 60, Folder 823)
        Copies of checks.
      - New York State/New York City Taxes (Box 60, Folder 824)
        New York State Income Tax Payments 1982-1983 Federal and FICA Income Tax Payments (Employees Withholding Taxes)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Taxes, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 825)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - Tax Rates - New York State, 1975-1991 (Box 60, Folder 826)
        New York City Real Estate Taxes.
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Taxes - Form WRS-2 - "Quarterly Report of Wages Paid to Each Employee" (Box 61, Folder 827)
        Tax Year: 1978-1991
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Taxes - Form W-2 - "Reconciliation of Tax Withheld" (Box 61, Folder 828)
        Tax Years: 1983-1991
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Department of Labor - SUI (Unemployment Insurance), 1983-1992 (Box 61, Folder 829)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State and Local Taxes - 1985 Monthly and Quarterly Report (Box 61, Folder 830)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Form 1099 Misc. - Transmittal of Form IT-2102-4 (Box 61, Folder 831)
        Tax Years: 1989, 1991
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - New York State Taxes - Forms WT-1, WT4A and WT4B - Quarterly Withholding, 1992-1994 (Box 61, Folder 832)
      - New York State/New York City Taxes - Employers Return of Tax Withheld, 1987-1993, 1995 (Box 61, Folder 833)
  - Membership, 1958-1995; 2.2; 5.45 Cubic Feet 13 document cases
    The majority of the Membership records comprise chronological documentation of dues collected, prospective members, structure of fees and membership lists as well as resignations and removals covering the entire lifespan of the Association from 1958-1994. Documentation of mailings sent to the membership and membership promotion and recruitment is also available from the late 1970s through the early 1990s.
    - L. Porter Moore - Membership Folder, 1958-1961 (Box 62, Folder 834)
      L. Porter Moore is D-LMA Vice President Civic Affairs.
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1958 (Box 62, Folder 835)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1959 (Box 62, Folder 836)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-April 1960 (Box 62, Folder 837)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, May-December 1960 (Box 62, Folder 838)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1961-1962 (Box 62, Folder 839)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1963 (Box 62, Folder 840)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 841)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-June 1965 (Box 62, Folder 842)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, July-December 1965 (Box 63, Folder 843)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1966 (Box 63, Folder 844)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1967 (Box 63, Folder 845)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 846)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-June 1969 (Box 63, Folder 847)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, July-December 1969 (Box 63, Folder 848)
    - Membership - Dues, Schedule and History of, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 849)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-April 1970 (Box 64, Folder 850)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, May-December 1970 (Box 64, Folder 851)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 852)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-May 1972 (Box 64, Folder 853)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, June-August 1972 (Box 64, Folder 854)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, September-December 1972 (Box 64, Folder 855)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-June 1973 (Box 64, Folder 856)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, July-December 1973 (Box 64, Folder 857)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-April 1974 (Box 65, Folder 858)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, May-December 1974 (Box 65, Folder 859)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, 1975 (Box 65, Folder 860)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-May 1976 (Box 65, Folder 861)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, June-December 1976 (Box 65, Folder 862)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-April 1977 (Box 65, Folder 863)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, May-December 1977 (Box 65, Folder 864)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, January-May 1978 (Box 65, Folder 865)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., June-December 1978 (Box 66, Folder 866)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-June 1979 (Box 66, Folder 867)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., July-December 1979 (Box 66, Folder 868)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-May 1980 (Box 66, Folder 869)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., June-December 1980 (Box 66, Folder 870)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-May 1981 (Box 66, Folder 871)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., July-December 1981 (Box 66, Folder 872)
    - Membership, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 873)
      Contains mainly membership lists, dues, and membership summary. There is very little correspondence except occasional copies of the general dues letters sent to the membership.
    - Membership Update, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 874)
    - Past Due Schedule Payments, 1979-1982 (Box 66, Folder 875)
    - Membership, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 876)
    - Membership, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 877)
    - Membership, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 878)
    - Membership, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 879)
    - Membership, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 880)
    - Membership, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 881)
    - Membership, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 882)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-April 1990 (Box 67, Folder 883)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., May-December 1990 (Box 67, Folder 884)
    - Membership - Dues Increase Proposal, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 885)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., 1991 (Box 67, Folder 886)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-April 1992 (Box 67, Folder 887)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., May-December 1992 (Box 67, Folder 888)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., January-April 1993 (Box 68, Folder 889)
    - Membership - Dues, Prospects, etc., May-December 1993 (Box 68, Folder 890)
    - Membership - Annual Membership Summary, 1983-1994 (Box 68, Folder 891)
    - Membership - Dues Sheets, 1983-1993 (Box 68, Folder 892)
    - Membership - Follow Up, 1993-1994 (Box 68, Folder 893)
    - Membership - General, 1977-1993 (Box 68, Folder 894)
      Includes: potential members lists, members lists, foreign corporations downtown list, Directors lists, minutes from various meetings, etc.
    - Membership - Lists (Members, Directors, Committees, etc.), 1990-1993, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 835)
    - Membership - Lists (Members, Directors, Committees, etc.), 1994, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 896)
    - Membership - Structure, 1994 (Box 69, Folder 897)
    - Member Mailings, 1977-1978 (Box 69, Folder 898)
    - Member Mailings, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 899)
    - Member Mailings, 1980 (Box 69, Folder 900)
    - Member Mailings, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 901)
    - Member Mailings, 1982 (Box 69, Folder 902)
    - Member Mailings - Sample Letters, 1982-1990 (Box 69, Folder 903)
    - Member Mailings, 1983 (Box 69, Folder 904)
    - Member Mailings, 1984 (Box 69, Folder 905)
    - Member Mailings, 1985 (Box 70, Folder 906)
      Includes Vietnam Veterans Parade poster, mailed April 16, 1985.
    - Member Mailings, 1986 (Box 70, Folder 907)
    - Member Mailings, 1987 (Box 70, Folder 908)
    - Member Mailings, 1988 (Box 70, Folder 909)
    - Member Mailings, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 910)
      Photo of American Merchant Marines Memorial sculpture by "Marisol" (to be located at Pier A) removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 16.
    - Member Mailings, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 911)
    - Member Mailings, 1991 (Box 70, Folder 912)
    - Member Mailings, 1992 (Box 70, Folder 913)
    - Member Mailings, 1993 (Box 70, Folder 914)
    - Member Mailings, 1994-1995 (Box 71, Folder 915)
      Includes Carl Weisbrod's "Draft Work Plan" for the Alliance for Downtown New York, October 24, 1994.
    - Member Mailings - DLMA Reports, 1991, 1992, 1994 (Box 71, Folder 916)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion Drive (& Lists), 1976 (Box 71, Folder 917)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion Drive, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 918)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion, 1978-1982 (Box 71, Folder 919)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion - Membership Invitations, 1980-1983 (Box 71, Folder 920)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion, 1983-1989 (Box 71, Folder 921)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 922)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 923)
    - Promotion - Foreign Banks - Membership Drive, 1988-1991 (Box 72, Folder 924)
    - Promotion - Foreign Companies in Downtown, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 925)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion - Delinquent Accounts and Target Lists for New Accounts, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 926)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion - Membership Invitations, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 927)
    - Promotion - Membership Promotion - Membership Invitations, 1992-1993 (Box 72, Folder 928)
    - Promotion - Membership Recruitment Study, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 929)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1958-1963 (Box 72, Folder 930)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1964-1970 (Box 72, Folder 931)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1971-1974 (Box 73, Folder 932)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1975-1977 (Box 73, Folder 933)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1978-1980 (Box 73, Folder 934)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1981-1985 (Box 73, Folder 935)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1986-1989 (Box 73, Folder 936)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1990-1991 (Box 73, Folder 937)
    - Membership - Resignations and Removals, 1992-1994 (Box 74, Folder 938)
    - Members (Contributions), 1958-1984 (Box 74, Folder 939)
      Bound ledger book.
    - Ex-Members (Dues and Contributions), 1958-1977 (Box 74, Folder 940)
    - Non-Members (Contributions), 1959-1962 (Box 74, Folder 941)
  - Projects, 1957-1995; 2.3; 42.125 Cubic Feet 121 document cases
    Projects are listed alphabetically by subject or by the name of the applicable organization.
    This subseries represents the overwhelming majority of the collection. It provides documentation of the Association's plans to redevelop and revitalize Lower Manhattan as a powerful business and financial center and to transform the community through a broadening residential population and growing opportunities for all the amenities of residential life including art, education, entertainment, health care, and many critical projects such as the World Trade Center, the Brooklyn Bridge Southeast and Southwest redevelopment areas, the heliport, Manhattan Landing, Nassau Street Mall, South Street Seaport and other downtown museums, community organizations such as the Lower Manhattan Cultural Council and the Lower Manhattan Marketing Association, Murry Bergtraum High School and the downtown campus of Pace University (identified as Pace College), a variety of traffic and transportation improvements, as well as DLMA's involvement with the Lower Manhattan Project and the 1993 "Plan for Lower Manhattan." These files also document the Association's interest in and recommendation of several major projects that never came to fruition such as Westway and the Lower Manhattan Expressway.
    - Academy of Finance (New York City Board of Education), 1983-1985, 1988 (Box 75, Folder 942)
    - "Action Committee for Lower Manhattan", 1993-1994 (Box 75, Folder 943)
      Revitalization of downtown through the adaptive re-use of existing office buildings. The Action Committee was initiated by the "Empty Building Syndrome" symposium, October 21, 1993.
    - Adopt-A-Station, 1976-1988 (Box 75, Folder 944)
      RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 17.
    - DLMA Advocacy - Letters and Testimony, 1991-1992 (Box 75, Folder 945)
    - DLMA Advocacy - Letters and Testimony, 1993-1994 (Box 75, Folder 946)
    - Alliance for the Arts - Non-Profit Cultural Facility Development and Management Study Proposal, 1994 (Box 75, Folder 947)
      Feasibility of establishing an entity to manage non-profit cultural facilities in New York City.
    - American Express Company, 1977-1986 (Box 75, Folder 948)
    - American Merchant Marine Library Association, 1984-1987 (Box 75, Folder 949)
    - American Merchant Mariners' Memorial, Inc., 1987-1991 (Box 75, Folder 950)
      Photos of planned memorial removed. See RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1081, Box 1, Folder 18.
    - American Stock Exchange, 1977-1980 (Box 76, Folder 951)